Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Score Collection, circa 1940-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Arrangements and editions of works by other composers, 1940-1987, II; Item 105-123
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Czardas, piano (1884). Csárdás obstiné; arranged Csárdás obstiné (1884) :for wind quintet 1985, 1 manuscript score (19 pages); 28 cm (Box 9, Item 110)
    Photocopy of original piano version of work (leaves 38-48) inserted.
  - Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 Czardas, piano (1884). Csárdás obstiné; arranged Csárdás obstiné 1985, 5 manuscript parts; 32 cm (Box 9, Item 111)
    Manuscript (Ink).
    Originally for piano; arr. for woodwind quintet.
  - MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908 Piano music. Selections; arranged Three pieces by Edward MacDowell: arranged for oboe and piano 1983, 1 manuscript score (13 pages); 29 cm; Alternate title: Pieces by Edward MacDowell (Box 9, Item 112)
    "June 6, 1983"--Colophon.
    Contents: The brook, op. 43, no. 1 -- To a wild rose, op. 51, no. 1 -- From Uncle Remus, op. 51, no. 7.
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 Präludien und Fugen, piano, op. 35. Nr. 5; arranged Praeludium et fuga no. 5 in fa minore for 2 vlns, 2 vlas and vc 1974, 1 manuscript score (13, 4, 16 pages); 24-26 x 36 cm; Alternate title: Title on envelope: Prelude & fugue no. 5 in f minor, transcription for small ensemble (Box 9, Item 113)
    Originally for piano; arr. for two instrumentations. Praeludium: for 2 oboes, English horn, bassoon, 4 horns, 2 violins, 2 violas, violoncello; Fuga: for 2 violins, 2 violas, violoncello.
    Includes two versions of the praeludium: the first (13 pages) for winds and strings; the second (4 pages) for string quintet, incomplete.
    "7/22, 23/74."
  - Morton, Jelly Roll, -1941 Big foot ham; arranged Big foot ham :1923 1984, 1 manuscript score (17 pages) + 4 parts; 35 cm (Box 9, Item 114)
    Holograph (Photocopy); Vellum ink masters of parts.
    At end: May 31, 1984.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged Red, hot and Cole :8 songs 1987, 1 manuscript score (102 pages); 36 cm (Box 10, Item 115)
    "Commissioned by the Eastman School of Music."
    Contents: At long last love -- Find me a primitive man -- Cherry pies ought to be you -- Fresh as a daisy -- Goodbye, little dream, goodbye -- Where, oh where -- You don't remind me -- Ridin' high.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged Red, hot and Cole :8 songs 1987, 1 manuscript score (5, 13 pages); 36 cm (Box 10, Item 116)
    For oboe, percussion, and strings; vocal part not indicated.
    Contains only two songs.
    "8.87"--End of Cherry pies.
    Contents: Cherry pies [ought to be you] -- [Find me] a primitive man.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged Red, hot & Cole 1987, 5 manuscript parts; 28 cm; Alternate title: Red, hot and Cole (Box 10, Item 117)
    Title from envelope.
    Song no. 3 (Cherry pies ought to be you) wanting.
    String parts only (Smit arranged the songs for oboe/English horn, string orchestra, and percussion).
    Contents: At long last love -- Find me a primitive man -- Fresh as a daisy -- Goodbye, little dream, goodbye -- Where, oh where -- You don't remind me -- Ridin' high.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged Love songs without words :for woodwind quintet 1974?, 1 manuscript score (48 leaves); 28 cm (Box 10, Item 118)
    For flute or alto flute, oboe or English horn, clarinet, horn, and bassoon.
    "Rental library, Carl Fischer, Inc."
    "9/13/74, Bflo., N.Y."--Colophon.
    Contents: At long last love -- Find me a primitive man -- Use your imagination -- Ridin' high.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged At long last love ;Find me a primitive man; Use your imagination; Ridin' high 1974?, 1 manuscript score (3, 4, 6 pages); 25 x 36 cm (Box 10, Item 119)
    "8/28/74"--At end of 2nd song; "8/29/74"--at end of 3rd song.
    Additional 4 leaves of sketches inserted.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections; arranged Cole Porter songs: arranged for small ensemble 1974, 1 manuscript score (various pagings); 25 x 35 cm (Box 10, Item 120)
    Contents: At long last love -- Find me a primitive man (8/24/74) -- Use your imagination (8/13/74) -- Ridin' high (8/14/74) -- It's bad for me -- Do I love you? -- You don't remind me [incomplete?] -- You're sensational (8/15/74) -- Goodbye, little dream, goodbye (8/14/74).
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Romances, oboe, piano, op. 94; arranged Three romances, op. 94: for oboe solo and orchestra 1977, 1 manuscript score (25 pages); 36 cm (Box 10, Item 121)
    Originally for oboe (or violin) and piano; accompaniment arranged for orchestra.
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 Jeu de cartes. Danse finale; arranged Finale: the triumph of the hearts: from Jeu de cartes (1936) 1950, 1 score (10 pages); 35 cm; Alternate title: Triumph of the hearts Alternate title: Finale from Jeu de cartes (Box 10, Item 122)
    Originally for orchestra; arranged for piano.
    "January 17, 1950, Elmsford, NY"--End of score.
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 Vesna svi︠a︡shchennai︠a︡. Velikai︠a︡ svi︠a︡shchennai︠a︡ pli︠a︡ska; arranged Danse sacrale: from Le sacre du printemps 194-?, [10] pages of music; 32 cm (Box 10, Item 123)
- Compositions by other composers marked for performance by Leo Smit, circa 1940-1987, III; Item 124-132
  Arranged alphabetically by composer's name
  - Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945 Sonatas, pianos (2), percussion Sonata for two pianos and percussion 1942, 2 scores (96 pages) + 1 part (24 pages); 31 cm (Box 11, Item 124)
    For 2 pianos, 3 timpani, xylophone, side drum with snares, side drum without snares, cymbal suspended, pair of cymbals, bass drum, triangle, tam-tam.
    "This work exists in two versions--the first, as in the present score, Sonata for two pianos and percussion; the second, with an orchestral accompaniment, entitled Concerto for two pianos with orchestra. The piano parts in the orchestral version differ in some instances from the version without orchestra. These passages are printed in small type [underneath the corresponding parts in the version without orchestra]"--Page [3].
    Duration: circa 24:30.
    Pl. nos.: B. & H. 8675, B. & H. 8816.
    Score marked with performance indications by Leo Smit. Markings reflect preparation of the piece by Smit with the composer.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 Fantasien, piano, mixed voices, orchestra, op. 80, C minor Chor-Fantasie für Klavier, Chor und Orchester, op. 80 Wiesbaden: Breitkopf & Härtel, [19--], Solo piano part (pages 1-3); orchestral score (pages 4-56) (Box 11, Item 125)
    Part prepared for performance by Leo Smit; includes additional photocopied inserts and markings.
    Program from Oct. 1978 Brockport Keyboard Festival inserted.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 Piano music. Selections Various piano works: including bagatelles complete, rondo a cappriccio, various preludes and phantasy 197-?, 1 score (103 pages); 31 cm. (Box 11, Item 126)
    Includes thematic index.
    Contents: Seven bagatelles, op. 33 --Two preludes, op. 39 --Two rondos, op. 51 --Phantasy, op. 77 --Polonaise, op. 89 --Eleven new bagatelles, op. 119 --Six bagatelles, op. 126 --Rondo a capriccio, op. 129 --Andante --Praeludium --Rondo.
  - Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924 Elegy, violoncello, piano, op. 24 Elegy, for cello and piano, opus 24 / [edited by] Leonard Rose New York: International Music Co., 1977, 1 score (8 pages) + 1 part (1 leaf); 31 cm (Box 11, Item 127)
    Marked for performance by Leo Smit.
  - Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937 Histoires naturelles / paroles de Jules Renard Paris: A. Durand; Philadelphia, Pa.: Elkan Vogel, [1956], 1907, 1 score (23 pages); 32 cm (Box 11, Item 128)
    Vocal part marked for performance
  - Rorem, Ned, 1923- Snake / [text by] Theodore Roethke New York: Henmar Press: Sole selling agents, C.F. Peters, 1963, 1 score (5 pages); 30 cm (Box 11, Item 129)
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 Ragtime; arranged Rag-time: for eleven instruments 1920, 1 score (12 pages); 31 cm (Box 11, Item 130)
    Photocopy (Schott Pl. no. 30929) of Hindemith's Ragtime, from his piano suite "1922", inserted.
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893 Sonatas, piano, op. 37, G major Sonate pour piano seul, op. 37 Moscou: P. Jurgenson, [1879], 51 pages of music; 34 cm (Box 11, Item 131)
    Marked for performance by Leo Smit
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 32, E♭ major; arranged Conzert, Es dur, für Pianoforte und Orchester, op. 32 between 1903 and 1941, 1 score (39 pages); 34 cm. (Box 11, Item 132)
    Inserted: 1st movement cadenza from "C. M. v. Weber's Clavierconcerte mit Orchesterbegleitung ... bearbeitet und Herrn Ernst Ferdinand Menzel ... hochachtungsvoll gewidmet von Hans von Bülow." Bartholf Senff pl. no. 904.905.
- Scores by other composers with inscriptions to Leo Smit, 1944-1990, IV; Item 133-142
  Arranged alphabetically by composer name
  - Allanbrook, Douglas. New American preludes Five new American preludes: to the great American jazz singer Peggy Lee 1990, 1 score (15 pages); 35 cm; Alternate title: New American preludes Alternate title: American preludes (Box 12, Item 133)
    For piano.
    Reproduction of manuscript (copyist: Christina T. Davidson).
    Contents: Casually -- Dry & rhythmic: somewhat off-hand -- Slow & heartfelt -- Flowing -- Perky and then passionate.
  - Allanbrook, Douglas. Night pieces Five night pieces: for piano 198-?, 1 score (38 pages); 28 cm; Alternate title: Night pieces (Box 12, Item 134)
    Reproduction of copyist's manuscript
    Contents: Night garden -- Night sky -- Night alarms -- Night birds -- Night patrol.
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 Anniversaries. Selections 16 [i.e. 18] anniversaries 1989?, 1 score (38 unnumbered pages); 28 cm; Alternate title: Anniversaries (Box 12, Item 135)
    Compiled by Leo Smit.
    Includes three copies of "For Leo Smit": 2 photocopies of the composer's holograph score and 1 photocopy of the score as published by Jalni Publications, 1989. This latter score bears an inscription from the composer to Leo Smit.
    Included: 2 photocopies of an inscription from the composer to Leo Smit and 1 photocopy of a handwritten note from Bernstein to Smit.
    Contents: For Aaron Copland -- For Johnny Mehegan -- For Lukas Foss -- For David Diamond -- For William Schuman -- For Paul Bowles -- In memoriam: Alfred Eisner -- For my sister, Shirley -- In memoriam: Nathalie Koussevitzky -- For Elizabeth B. Ehrman -- For Felicia Montealegre -- For Sergei Koussevitzky -- For Helen Coates -- For Elizabeth Rudolf -- For Sandy Gellhorn -- For Susanna Kyle -- For Leo Smit -- For my daughter, Nina.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Tender land. Promise of living. Vocal score The promise of living: quintet from "The tender land,": arranged for mixed chorus with piano duet accompaniment [New York]: Boosey & Hawkes, 1954, 1 vocal score (19 pages); 27 cm (Box 12, Item 136)
    Bears inscription from the composer to Leo Smit
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Tender land. Vocal score The tender land: opera in three acts [New York]: Boosey & Hawkes, 1956, 1 vocal score (203 pages); 31 cm (Box 12, Item 136a)
    Title page bears inscription from Aaron Copland to Leo Smit, April 1956
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Sonatas, violin, piano Sonata for violin and piano London: Boosey & Hawkes, 1944, 1 score (33 pages) and 1 part; 30 cm (Box 12, Item 137)
    Inscription from the composer to Leo Smit (1981) on t.p.
  - Del Tredici, David Scherzo, piano, 4 hands Scherzo for piano, four hands [United States]: Boosey and Hawkes, 1975, 1 score (15 pages); 31 cm (Box 12, Item 138)
  - Kolb, Barbara Appello: for piano [New York]: Boosey & Hawkes, [1978], 1 score (17 pages); 31 cm (Box 12, Item 139)
  - Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991 Echoes from Austria, for piano New York: Rongwen Music, [1959], 1 score (12 pages); 31 cm (Box 12, Item 140)
  - Kubik, Gail, 1914-1984 Heure des adieux L'heure des adieux, ou Mieux, d'au-revoir 1968, 1 score (2 leaves); 35 cm; Alternate title: Heure des adieux Alternate title: Mieux, d'au-revoir (Box 12, Item 141)
    "To the memory of Pope John XXIII."
    "12 Juin, 1963, Paris"--Colophon.
  - Shapero, Harold, 1920-2013 Happy birthday Mister La Sol Happy birthday Mr. La Sol: to Leo Smit 1987, 1 score (3 leaves); 28 cm; Alternate title: Happy birthday Mister La Sol (Box 12, Item 142)
    Title from inscription in caption.
    Includes 4 photocopies of holograph of score dated December 15, 1987 at end of score.
- Scores autographed by Leo Smit, 1949, V; Item 143
  - Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741 Concertos. Selections Quattro concerti: autografi della Sächsische Landesbibliothek di Dresda Siena: Accademia musicale chigiana, 1949, 1 score (Facsims. of holographs) (Box 12, Item 143)
    Bears inscription by Leo Smit
- Additional scores received with the collection, 1938-1991, VI; Item 144-147
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990 Songs. Selections Lenny memorial :5.29.91, Los Angeles 1991, 1 folder; 28 cm (Box 12, Item 144)
    For voice and piano.
    Contents: I hate music. I: My mother says that babies come in bottles; II: Jupiter has seven moons -- III: I hate music -- Silhouette -- Piccola serenata -- Somewhere -- I am easily assimilated: from Candide -- I feel pretty -- Tonight -- What a terrible movie: [from Trouble in Tahiti] -- Make our garden grow: from Candide.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Billy the Kid. Selections; arranged Billy the Kid 1938, 2 manuscript scores (63 pages); 38 cm (Box 13, Item 145)
    Excerpts from ballet originally for orchestra, arr. for 2 pianos.
    Duration: circa 34:00.
    Score marked with orchestration.
    Both scores marked by Leo Smit for performance.
    At end: Finis July-Sept. 1938 Paris, New York, Peterboro, N.H.
    Contents: Introduction. The open prairie -- Scene Ia. Street in a frontier town -- Billy's variation -- Scene IIa. The card game -- Scene IIb. The battle -- Scene IIc. Macabre dance -- Scene IId. Billy in prison -- Scene IIIc. Capture and death of Billy -- Scene IIId. Pieta -- Coda.
  - Porter, Cole, 1891-1964 Songs. Selections Ten songs 1974, 10 scores; 28-36 cm (Box 13, Item 146)
    Accompanied by typescript (1 leaf) list of Porter songs, captioned "Manuscripts, ozilids given to Mr. Leo Smith [sic], May 17, 1974."
    Contents: You don't remind me -- Pick me up and lay me down -- What a fair things is a woman -- The perfume of love -- Why should I trust you? -- The ragtime pipes of Pan -- Slow sinks the sun -- We're on the road to Athens -- Midsummer night -- Mysteriously.
  - Raksin, David. Songs. Selections Sixteen songs 1989, 16 scores; 28-37 cm (Box 13, Item 147)
    Date from postage on envelope.
    Contents: The bad and the beautiful: theme of the M-G-M film / words by Dory Langdon -- How shall we begin?: from the Paramount picture Too late blues: publication version / lyric by Jay Livingston, Ray Evans -- I wish: from If the shoe fits, musical / words by June Carroll -- If you remember me / words, Ben Perry -- Lonely rider: from the Paramount picture Will Penny / words by Robert Wells -- Love has many faces / lyric by Mack David -- Mirror, mirror, mirror: theme from A Big hand for the little lady / lyric by Johnny Mercer -- My business man: [from] If the shoe fits / words by June Carroll -- Slowly: from the 20th Century Fox production Fallen angel / lyric by Kermit Goell -- Some days seem so beautiful: from the film Glass houses / lyric, Arthur Hamilton -- Sometimes I wonder what I'm doing here -- Sylvia: as sung by Paul Anka in the Paramount picture Sylvia / words by Paul Francis Webster -- Tell me that you love me -- That's loneliness: theme of the Paramount film Too late blues: original title as used in film: A song after sundown / lyric by Jay Livingston, Ray Evans.
- Additional scores received after original processing was completed, circa 1900-2016, VII; Item 149-185
  These scores were received as gifts after the original processing and item cataloging was completed. They consist of scores of Smit's compositions as well as scores by other composers, either marked by him for performance or inscribed by the composers to Smit.
  Arranged in order of receipt, then arranged within batches by either composer name or by title, with Smit's compositions first.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Love is a sickness [1947], 1 manuscript score (Ozalid copy) (Box 13, Item 148)
    Gift of Sarah Whittaker Peters (Leo Smit was Sarah's piano teacher at Sarah Lawrence College in the 1950s). "Dedicated to Art and Sally". Score faded to extent that it is no longer fully legible.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act I. Vocal score The alchemy of love: a comic opera in three acts. Act I / libretto by Fred Hoyle 1968, 1 manuscript vocal score (a-b, 94 pages); 36 cm (Box 14, Item 149)
    Score includes several markings: additions and changes to text.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Alchemy of love. Act III. Vocal score The alchemy of love, or, The daemon servant's retribution: a comic opera in three acts. Act III / libretto by Fred Hoyle; music by Leo Smit 1960, 1 manuscript vocal score (pages 173-307); 36 cm (Box 14, Item 150)
    At end of score: Oct. 20, 1960, Los Angeles.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Caedmon. Vocal score Caedmon, according to the Venerable Bede: a cantata for 3 solo voices, male chorus and orchestra: 1952-72 / words by Anthony Hecht 1972, 1 manuscript vocal score (60 pages); 36 cm (Box 14, Item 151)
    Inscribed by Smit to Menise Smith.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Capriccio, string orchestra Capriccio for string orchestra 1958, 1 manuscript score (41 pages); 36 cm (Box 14, Item 152)
    Composer's typescript note affixed to verso of front cover page.
    Contains performance markings.
    At end of score: February 27, 1958, West Hollywood.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Beyond circumference. After great pain, a formal feeling comes; arr. After great pain, a formal feeling comes 1990?, 1 manuscript score (7 leaves); 31 x 38 cm (Box 14, Item 153)
    Holograph (Pencil)
    Text by Emily Dickinson.
    Originally for voice and piano; accompaniment arranged for instrumental ensemble.
    Possibly incomplete.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Childe Emilie. I cried at pity, not at pain; arr. I cried at pity, not at pain 1990, 1 manuscript score (9 leaves); 31 x 38 cm (Box 14, Item 154)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Childe Emilie. Let us play yesterday; arr. Let us play yesterday 1990?, 1 manuscript score (13 leaves); 31 x 38 cm (Box 15, Item 155)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Childe Emilie. Up life's hill; arr. Up life's hill 1990, 1 manuscript score (1 leaf); 31 x 38 cm (Box 15, Item 156)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Ecstatic pilgrimage. Childe Emilie. We talked as girls do; arr. We talked as girls do 1990, 1 manuscript score (6 leaves); 31 x 38 cm (Box 15, Item 157)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 If I can stop one heart from breaking If I can stop one heart from breaking / words by Emily Dickinson 1993, 1 leaf of music; 28 cm (Box 15, Item 158)
    Photocopy of Hymn 292 from Singing the living tradition, a Unitarian hymnal.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Motets Four motets for two flues, voice and violin 1955, 2 manuscript scores (6 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 159)
    Holograph (Ozalid)
    At end of score: May 1955, N.Y.C.
    Translated from German folk lyrics by Sylvia Wright; one copy has an alternative translation added in pencil.
    Content: Wake up, my love -- Oh Katharine, dearest -- Venus, you and your son -- Oh Mother, tell me how to die.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Quartet, strings Quartet for strings (1938/83) 1983, 1 manuscript score (54 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 160)
    Holograph (Photocopy)
    Marked with changes.
    Label on verso of front cover: Commissioned by and dedicated to the Camenae Quartet.
    At end of score: 12.10.83.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sequence Sequence: three songs for voice and piano (1959/65) / poems by Theodore Roethke 1965, 1 manuscript score (9, 5, 9 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 161)
    Holograph (Ozalid copy)
    Contents: In a dark time -- In evening air -- Sequel.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Sequence. In a dark time; arr. Sequence. I. In a dark time 1965, 1 manuscript score (13 pages); 25 x 36 cm (Box 15, Item 162)
    Text by Theodore Roethke not entered on score.
    Originally for voice and piano; accompaniment arranged for instrumental ensemble: flute, clarinet, horn, trumpet; trombone, harp, violin, violoncello.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Symphony of dances and songs for orchestra 1981, 1 score (149 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 163)
    Marked for performance.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Thinngs all over Thinngs all over: for soprano and piano 1983, 1 score (5 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 164)
    Text by Carla Rodman.
    Inscribed by Smit to Jan DeGaetani.
    Marked with changes, including the ending.
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Thinngs all over; arr. Thinngs all over: for voice, oboe and piano 1983, 1 score (5 pages); 35 cm (Box 15, Item 165)
    Inscribed by Smit to "Jan and Phil".
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Virginia sampler; arr. Virginia sampler: a ballet arranged for two pianos by the composer 1977, 1 manuscript score (40 pages); 36 cm (Box 15, Item 166)
  - Smit, Leo, 1921-1999 Yerma: a ballet from the play by Garcia Lorca 1946, 1 score (38 pages); 38 cm + 3 parts; 32 cm (Box 16, Item 167)
    Score: Holograph (Ozalid copy).
    Parts for bassoon, flute, trumpet(B♭), all marked for performance.
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Second hurricane. Selections; arr. Piano partita from The Second hurricane, arranged for piano solo by Leo Smit 1968, 1 manuscript score (13 pages); 35 cm (Box 16, Item 168)
    Duration: 12 min.
    At end of score: 6/18/68, Los Angeles
    Contents: Overture -- Gyp's song -- Two willow hill -- Introduction and Jeff's song -- Fat's song -- Finale.
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Romances, oboe, piano, op. 94; arranged Three romances, op. 94: for solo oboe and chamber orchestra / arranged by Leo Smit 2016, 1 score (62 pages); 31 cm (Box 16, Item 169)
    Originally for oboe (or violin) and piano; accompaniment arranged for chamber orchestra by Leo Smit.
    Score prepared from the manuscript for premiere performance by Dr. Robert Howe, May 21, 2017.
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Romances, oboe, piano, op. 94; arranged Three romances, op. 94 / arr. Leo Smit 2016, 31 parts; 31 cm (Box 16, Item 170)
    Complete set of bound parts, including multiple string parts, prepared from the manuscript for premiere performance by Dr. Robert Howe, May 21, 2017.
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856 Romances, oboe, piano, op. 94; arranged Three romances, op. 94: for solo oboe and chamber orchestra / arranged by Leo Smit 2016, 1 score (62 pages) and 14 parts; 28 cm (Box 16, Item 171)
    Complete set of unbound score and parts, prepared from the manuscript for premiere performance by Dr. Robert Howe, May 21, 2017.
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971 Greeting prelude; arranged Greeting prelude (1955) / arranged for solo piano by Leo Smit 1962, 1 manuscript score (2 pages); 30 cm (Box 17, Item 172)
    Holograph (Ink)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian Wohltemperierte Klavier, 2. T. Das wohltemperierte Klavier 2. Teil (1744) Leipzig: Steingräber Verlag, undated, 1 score (133 pages); 32 cm (Box 17, Item 173)
    Typescript notes (2 leaves) by Leo Smit inserted.
    Score bears some markings.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827 33 variations en forme d'études 33 variations on a waltz by Diabelli: for piano solo op. 120 New York: Edwin F. Kalmus, undated, 1 score (32-63 pages); 33 cm (Box 17, Item 174)
    Bears performance markings and notes by Leo Smit on the versos of both covers. The notes consist of quotations from different texts to be read during performances of the work.